On the path that American children travel to adulthood,
في طريق سفر الأطفال الأمريكيين إلى البلوغ،
two institutions oversee the journey.
تشرف مؤسستان على الرحلة.
The first is the one we hear a lot about: college.
الأولى هي مؤسسة نسمع الكثير عنها: الكلية.
Some of you may remember the excitement that you felt
ربما يذكر بعضكم الإثارة التي شعرتم بها
when you first set off for college.
عندما انطلقتم للمرة الأولى نحو الكلية.
Some of you may be in college right now
ربما يكون بعضكم في الكلية الآن
and you're feeling this excitement at this very moment.
وتشعرون بهذه الإثارة في هذه اللحظة بالذات.
College has some shortcomings.
تملك الكلية بعض العيوب.
It's expensive; it leaves young people in debt.
إنها مكلفة؛ تُراكِم الديون على الشباب.
But all in all, it's a pretty good path.
ولكن بشكل عام، فإنها طريق جيد إلى حد ما.
Young people emerge from college with pride and with great friends
يخرج الشباب من الكليات بفخروبأصدقاء رائعين
and with a lot of knowledge about the world.
ومع كثير من المعرفة عن العالم.
And perhaps most importantly,
وربما الأكثر الأهمية هو،
a better chance in the labor market than they had before they got there.
فرصة في سوق العمل أفضل من تلك التي حصلوا عليها قبل الدخول هناك.
Today I want to talk about the second institution
أريد الحديث إليكم اليوم عن المؤسسة الثانية
overseeing the journey from childhood to adulthood in the United States.
التي تشرف على الرحلة من الطفولة إلى البلوغ في الولايات المتحدة.
And that institution is prison.
تلك المؤسسة هي السجن.
Young people on this journey are meeting with probation officers
يجتمع الشباب في هذه الرحلة بشرطة الآداب
instead of with teachers.
بدلًا من المعلمين.
They're going to court dates instead of to class.
يذهبون إلى جلسات المحاكمة بدلًا من الصفوف.
Their junior year abroad is instead a trip to a state correctional facility.
وتكون أول سنة لهم في الخارج رحلة إلى منشأة إصلاحية تديرها الدولة.
And they're emerging from their 20s
وهم يخرجون من العشرينات من عمرهم،
not with degrees in business and English,
ليس بشهادات في الأعمال واللغة الإنجليزية،
but with criminal records.
بل بسجلات جنائية.
This institution is also costing us a lot,
هذه المؤسسة تكلفنا الكثير أيضًا،
about 40,000 dollars a year
حوالي 40,000 دولار سنويًا
to send a young person to prison in New Jersey.
لإرسال شاب إلى السجن في نيوجيرسي.
But here, taxpayers are footing the bill
ولكن هنا، يُغطي دافعو الضرائب فواتيرهم
and what kids are getting is a cold prison cell
وما يحصل عليه الأطفال هو زنزانة سجن باردة
and a permanent mark against them when they come home
وعلامة دائمة ضدهم عند عودتهم إلى المنزل
and apply for work.
وتقديمهم للعمل.
There are more and more kids on this journey to adulthood
في الولايات المتحدة، هناك أطفال في هذه الرحلة إلى البلوغ
than ever before in the United States and that's because in the past 40 years,
أكثر من ذي قبل، وهذا بسبب أنه في الأربعين سنة الماضية
our incarceration rate has grown by 700 percent.
ارتفع معدل السجن عندنا بنسبة 700%.
I have one slide for this talk.
لدي شريحة واحدة لهذه المحادثة.
Here it is.
ها هي.
Here's our incarceration rate,
هذا هو معدل السجن عندنا،
about 716 people per 100,000 in the population.
حوالي 716 شخص لكل 100,000 من السكان.
Here's the OECD countries.
هذه دول منظمة التعاون والتنمية في الميدان الاقتصادي.
What's more, it's poor kids that we're sending to prison,
علاوة على ذلك، نحن نقوم بإرسال الأطفال المساكين إلى السجن،
too many drawn from African-American and Latino communities
الكثير منهم ينحدرون من مجتمعات الأمريكيين الأفارقة واللاتينيين
so that prison now stands firmly between the young people trying to make it
لذا فالسجن الآن يقف حائلًا بين الشباب الذين يحاولون الإنجاز
and the fulfillment of the American Dream.
وتحقيق الحلم الأمريكي.
The problem's actually a bit worse than this
المشكلة بصراحة أسوأ من هذا بقليل
'cause we're not just sending poor kids to prison,
لأننا لا نقوم بإرسال الأطفال المساكين إلى السجن فحسب،
we're saddling poor kids with court fees,
نحن نرهق هؤلاء الأطفال بتكاليف المحكمة،
with probation and parole restrictions,
مع تعليق العقوبة وإطلاق السراح المشروط،
with low-level warrants,
مع الكفالات منخفضة المستوى،
we're asking them to live in halfway houses and on house arrest,
نحن نطلب منهم العيش على مسافة بين المنازل والإقامة الجبرية،
and we're asking them to negotiate a police force
ونطلب منهم التفاوض مع قوات الشرطة
that is entering poor communities of color,
التي تدخل إلى المجتمعات الفقيرة ذات اللون،
not for the purposes of promoting public safety,
ليس بغرض تعزيز الأمن العام،
but to make arrest counts, to line city coffers.
بل للقيام بعدد من الاعتقالات، لتزيد الصناديق الحديدية في المدينة.
This is the hidden underside to our historic experiment in punishment:
هذا هو الجانب المظلم المخفي من تجربتنا التاريخية في العقاب:
young people worried that at any moment, they will be stopped, searched and seized.
فالشباب يخشون من أنهم سيتعرضون للتوقيف والتفتيش والسجن في أية لحظة.
Not just in the streets, but in their homes,
ليس في الشوارع فحسب، بل وهم في بيوتهم،
at school and at work.
وفي مدرستهم وأثناء عملهم.
I got interested in this other path to adulthood
اهتممت بهذا الطريق الثاني إلى البلوغ
when I was myself a college student
عندما كنتُ طالبة في الكلية
attending the University of Pennsylvania
في جامعة بنسلفانيا
in the early 2000s.
في بدايات الألفية الثانية.
Penn sits within a historic African-American neighborhood.
تقع بنسلفانيا في منطقة لأهلها أصول أفريقية أمريكية.
So you've got these two parallel journeys going on simultaneously:
إذًا لديكم هاتان الرحلتان المتوازيتان اللتان تستمران جنبًا إلى جنب:
the kids attending this elite, private university,
يذهب الأولاد إلى الجامعة الرائدة والخاصة،
and the kids from the adjacent neighborhood,
أما الأولاد من الحي المحاذي،
some of whom are making it to college,
ينجح بعضهم في الوصول إلى الكلية،
and many of whom are being shipped to prison.
ويُنقل الكثير منهم إلى السجن.
In my sophomore year, I started tutoring a young woman who was in high school
في السنة الثانية لي، بدأت بتدريس شابة كانت في المدرسة الثانوية
who lived about 10 minutes away from the university.
وكانت تسكن على بعد عشر دقائق من الجامعة.
Soon, her cousin came home from a juvenile detention center.
بعد وقت قليل، عاد ابن عمها إلى منزله من مركز احتجاز الأحداث.
He was 15, a freshman in high school.
كان يبلغ 15 عامًا، في أول ثانوي.
I began to get to know him and his friends and family,
بدأت بالتعرف عليه وعلى أصدقائه وعائلته،
and I asked him what he thought about me writing about his life
وسألته ماذا اعتقد بشأن كتابتي عن حياته
for my senior thesis in college.
لبحث تخرجي في الكلية.
This senior thesis became a dissertation at Princeton
هذا البحث أصبح أطروحة في جامعة برينستون
and now a book.
والآن أصبح كتابًا.
By the end of my sophomore year,
ومع نهاية سنتي الثانية،
I moved into the neighborhood and I spent the next six years
انتقلت للسكن في هذا الحي وقضيت الست سنوات التي تلت
trying to understand what young people were facing as they came of age.
أحاول فهم ما يواجهه الشباب عند بلوغهم.
The first week I spent in this neighborhood,
الأسبوع الأول الذي قضيته في هذا الحي،
I saw two boys, five and seven years old,
رأيت ولدين، أحدهما في الخامسة والآخر في السابعة من عمره،
play this game of chase,
يلعبان الشريدة "المطاردة"،
where the older boy ran after the other boy.
حيث يبدأ الولد الكبير باللحاق بالآخر.
He played the cop.
هو لعب دور الشرطي.
When the cop caught up to the younger boy,
عندما أمسك الشرطي بالولد الكبير،
he pushed him down,
دفعه أرضًا،
handcuffed him with imaginary handcuffs,
قيد يديه بأصفاد خيالية،
took a quarter out of the other child's pocket,
وأخرج ربع دولار من جيب الولد الثاني،
saying, "I'm seizing that."
وهو يقول "سأحتفظ به".
He asked the child if he was carrying any drugs
وسأل الطفل فيما إذا كان يحمل أية مخدرات
or if he had a warrant.
أو فيما لو كان يحمل رخصة.
Many times, I saw this game repeated,
رأيت هذه اللعبة تُعاد كثيرًا،
sometimes children would simply give up running,
في بعض الأوقات، يستسلم الأطفال عن الجري،
and stick their bodies flat against the ground
ويلصقون أجسادهم مستوية إلى الأرض
with their hands above their heads, or flat up against a wall.
ويجعلون أيديهم فوق رؤوسهم، أو يقفون بوجوههم إلى الحائط.
Children would yell at each other,
ربما يصيح الأطفال إلى بعضهم البعض
"I'm going to lock you up,
"سوف أحبسك،
I'm going to lock you up and you're never coming home!"
سوف أحبسك ولن تعود إلى المنزل أبدًا!"
Once I saw a six-year-old child pull another child's pants down
وذات مرة رأيت طفلًا ذا ست سنوات يشد بنطال طفل آخر إلى الأسفل
and try to do a cavity search.
ويحاول القيام بتفتيش التجويفات الجسدية.
In the first 18 months that I lived in this neighborhood,
في أول 18 شهرًا عشتها في ذلك الحي،
I wrote down every time I saw any contact between police
قمت بتسجيل كل مرة رأيت فيها أي احتكاك بين الشرطة
and people that were my neighbors.
والناس الذين كانوا جيراني.
So in the first 18 months,
إذًا في الـ 18 شهرًا الأولى،
I watched the police stop pedestrians or people in cars,
رأيت الشرطة تقوم بإيقاف المشاة أو الأشخاص في السيارات،
search people, run people's names,
تفتش الناس وتبحث عن أسمائهم
chase people through the streets,
وتلاحقهم في الشوارع،
pull people in for questioning,
وتأخذهم للتحقيق،
or make an arrest every single day, with five exceptions.
أو تقوم بعملية اعتقال بشكل يومي، مع خمس استثناءات.
Fifty-two times, I watched the police break down doors,
52 مرة، رأيت الشرطة تكسر الأبواب،
chase people through houses
تلاحق الناس في البيوت
or make an arrest of someone in their home.
أو تقوم باعتقال شخص ما في بيته.
Fourteen times in this first year and a half,
40 مرة في هذه السنة والنصف الأولى،
I watched the police punch, choke, kick, stomp on or beat young men
رأيت الشرطة تلكم وتخنق وتركل وتدوس وتضرب شبابًا
after they had caught them.
بعد أن قاموا بالإمساك بهم.
Bit by bit, I got to know two brothers,
وشيئًا فشيئا، تعرفت على الأخوين،
Chuck and Tim.
تشك وتيم.
Chuck was 18 when we met, a senior in high school.
كان تشك في الثامنة عشر عندما تقابلنا، في الصف الأول ثانوي.
He was playing on the basketball team and making C's and B's.
كان يلعب في فريق كرة السلة ويحصل على c و b في المواد الدراسية.
His younger brother, Tim, was 10.
كان أخوه الأصغر تيم في العاشرة من عمره.
And Tim loved Chuck; he followed him around a lot,
كان تيم يحب تشك؛ ويتبعه كثيرًا في الأرجاء،
looked to Chuck to be a mentor.
وينظر إلى أخيه تشيك كمعلم.
They lived with their mom and grandfather
وعاشا مع أمهما وجدهما
in a two-story row home with a front lawn and a back porch.
في بيت مكون من طابقين مع حديقة أمامية وشرفة خلفية.
Their mom was struggling with addiction all while the boys were growing up.
كانت أمهما تعاني من الإدمان بينما كان الولدان يكبران.
She never really was able to hold down a job for very long.
لم تكن قادرة فعلًا على الاستمرار بوظيفة لوقت طويل جدًا.
It was their grandfather's pension that supported the family,
كان معاش التقاعد الخاص بجدهم هو ما دعم العائلة،
not really enough to pay for food and clothes
لم يكن كافيًا بحق لدفع ثمن الطعام والملابس
and school supplies for growing boys.
ولوازم المدرسة للأولاد الذين يكبرون.
The family was really struggling.
كانت العائلة تعاني جدًا.
So when we met, Chuck was a senior in high school.
إذًا عندما تقابلنا، كان تشيك في أول ثانوي.
He had just turned 18.
كان قد أصبح للتو في الثامنة عشرة من عمره.
That winter, a kid in the schoolyard
في ذلك الشتاء، أطلق ولد في ملعب المدرسة
called Chuck's mom a crack whore.
لفظًا بذيئًا على أم تشك.
Chuck pushed the kid's face into the snow
قام تشك بدفع وجه الولد في الثلج
and the school cops charged him with aggravated assault.
واتهمته شرطة المدرسة بالاعتداء بالعنف.
The other kid was fine the next day,
في اليوم التالي كان الطفل الآخر بحالة جيدة،
I think it was his pride that was injured more than anything.
أظن أن كبرامته هي التي جُرحت أكثر من أي شيء.
But anyway, since Chuck was 18,
ولكن، لأن تشك كان في سن الـ 18،
this agg. assault case sent him to adult county jail
حالة الاعتداء بالعنف هذه أرسلته إلى سجن المقاطعة للبالغين
on State Road in northeast Philadelphia,
في ستيت رود شمالي فيلادلفيا،
where he sat, unable to pay the bail -- he couldn't afford it --
حيث جلس، غير قادر على دفع الكفالة -- لم يتحملها --
while the trial dates dragged on and on and on
بينما امتدت جلسات المحكمة طويلًا
through almost his entire senior year.
تقريبًا على مدار سنته الأولى.
Finally, near the end of this season,
وأخيرًا، قرب نهاية هذا الفصل،
the judge on this assault case threw out most of the charges
أسقط قاضي معظم التهم في قضية الاعتداء هذه
and Chuck came home
وعاد تشك إلى منزله
with only a few hundred dollars' worth of court fees hanging over his head.
مع رسوم المحكمة التي يبلغ مقدارها بضع مئات الدولارات والتي كانت تهدد حياته.
Tim was pretty happy that day.
كان تيم سعيدًا جدًا في ذلك اليوم.
The next fall, Chuck tried to re-enroll as a senior,
في الخريف التالي، حاول تشك إعادة الالتحاق في الصف الأول ثانوي،
but the school secretary told him that
ولكن سكرتير المدرسة أخبره بأنه
he was then 19 and too old to be readmitted.
في سن الـ 19 وأنه كبير جدًا على إعادة قبوله.
Then the judge on his assault case issued him a warrant for his arrest
ثم أصدر القاضي في قضية الاعتداء خاصته مذكرة اعتقال له
because he couldn't pay the 225 dollars in court fees
لأنه لم يستطع دفع مبلغ 225 دولار لقاء رسوم المحكمة
that came due a few weeks after the case ended.
التي حلّ ميعادها بعد بضعة أسابيع من انتهاء القضية.
Then he was a high school dropout living on the run.
ثم أصبح متوقفًا عن الدراسة الثانوية يعيش في الشوارع.
Tim's first arrest came later that year
حصل أول اعتقال لـتيم في وقت لاحق من تلك السنة
after he turned 11.
بعد أن أصبح في الحادية عشرة من عمره.
Chuck had managed to get his warrant lifted
قد استطاع تشك تسديد كفالته
and he was on a payment plan for the court fees
وكان يمشي على خطة لدفع رسوم المحكمة
and he was driving Tim to school in his girlfriend's car.
وكان يذهب بتيم في سيارة صديقته إلى المدرسة.
So a cop pulls them over, runs the car,
حسنًا، قام بشرطي بوقفهما والبحث عن السيارة
and the car comes up as stolen in California.
وتبين أن السيارة مسروقة في كاليفورنيا.
Chuck had no idea where in the history of this car it had been stolen.
لم يكن لتشك أدنى فكرة عن تاريخ هذه السيارة و أنها مسروقة.
His girlfriend's uncle bought it from a used car auction
اشتراها عم صديقته من مزاد للسيارات المستخدمة
in northeast Philly.
في شمال شرقي فيلادلفيا.
Chuck and Tim had never been outside of the tri-state,
لم يسبق لـتيم وتشك أبدًا أن خرجا من منطقة الولايات الثلاثة،
let alone to California.
ناهيكم عن كاليفورنيا.
But anyway, the cops down at the precinct
لكن على أية حال، الشرطة في مركز الاحتجاز
charged Chuck with receiving stolen property.
قامت بتوجيه تهم لـتشك باستلام ممتكات مسروقة.
And then a juvenile judge, a few days later,
ثم بعد أيام قليلة قام قاضي الأحداث
charged Tim, age 11,
بتوجيه تهم لتيم، البالغ 11 سنة،
with accessory to receiving a stolen property
بالاشتراك في استلام ممتلكات مسروقة
and then he was placed on three years of probation.
ثم تم وضعه تحت المراقبة لمدة ثلاث سنوات.
With this probation sentence hanging over his head,
ومع عقوبة المراقبة هذه التي تهدده،
Chuck sat his little brother down
أقعد تشك أخاه الصغير
and began teaching him how to run from the police.
وبدأ بتعليمه كيف يهرب من الشرطة.
They would sit side by side on their back porch
كانا يجلسان جنبًا إلى جنب في شرفتهم الخلفية
looking out into the shared alleyway
ينتبهان إلى الزقاق المشترك
and Chuck would coach Tim how to spot undercover cars,
ويقوم تشك بتعليم تيم كيف يرصد السيارات المتخفية،
how to negotiate a late-night police raid, how and where to hide.
كيف يتفاوض في هجوم للشرطة في آخر الليل، كيف وأين يختبئا.
I want you to imagine for a second
أريدكم أن تتخيلوا لثانية
what Chuck and Tim's lives would be like
ما ستكون عليه حياة تشك وتيم
if they were living in a neighborhood where kids were going to college,
لو كانا يعيشان في حي يذهب فيه الأولاد إلى الكلية،
not prison.
ليس إلى السجن.
A neighborhood like the one I got to grow up in.
حي كالذي حظيت بالنمو فيه.
Okay, you might say.
ربما تقولون حسنًا.
But Chuck and Tim, kids like them, they're committing crimes!
لكن تشك وتيم، أولاد مثلهم، هم يرتكبون الجرائم!
Don't they deserve to be in prison?
ألا يستحقان السجن؟
Don't they deserve to be living in fear of arrest?
ألا يستحقان العيش في حالة خوف من الاعتقال؟
Well, my answer would be no.
حسنًا، إجابتي ستكون لا.
They don't.
لا يستحقان.
And certainly not for the same things that other young people
وبالتأكيد ليس للأشياء نفسها التي يفعلها شباب آخرون
with more privilege are doing with impunity.
بامتيازات أكثر وبحصانة.
If Chuck had gone to my high school,
إن ذهب تشك إلى مدرستي الثانوية،
that schoolyard fight would have ended there,
ذلك الشجار في ملعب المدرسة كان لينتهي هناك
as a schoolyard fight.
كشجار في ملعب المدرسة.
It never would have become an aggravated assault case.
لم يكن ليصبح قضية اعتداء بالضرب.
Not a single kid that I went to college with
ليس لأي ولد في الكلية التي ذهبت إليها
has a criminal record right now.
سجل إجرامي الآن.
Not a single one.
لا أحد إطلاقًا.
But can you imagine how many might have if the police had stopped those kids
هل بإمكانكم تخيل عدد من يحتمل أن يمتلكوا سجلًا لو أوقفت الشرطة هؤلاء الأولاد
and searched their pockets for drugs as they walked to class?
وقامت بتفتيش جيوبهم بحثًا عن المخدرات عند دخولهم إلى الفصل؟
Or had raided their frat parties in the middle of the night?
أو قامت بالهجوم على حفلاتهم في منتصف الليل؟
Okay, you might say.
ربما تقولون حسنًا.
But doesn't this high incarceration rate
لكن ألا يدل معدل السجن العالي هذا
partly account for our really low crime rate?
جزئيًا على تدني معدل الجريمة لدينا؟
Crime is down. That's a good thing.
الجريمة في انخفاض. هذا جيد.
Totally, that is a good thing. Crime is down.
تمامًا، هذا شيء جيد. الجريمة في انخفاض.
It dropped precipitously in the '90s and through the 2000s.
لقد انخفضت بشكل كبير في التسعينات وخلال الألفينات.
But according to a committee of academics
ولكن حسب لجنة للأكاديمين
convened by the National Academy of Sciences last year,
عقدتها الأكاديمية الوطنية للعلوم في العام السابق،
the relationship between our historically high incarceration rates
العلاقة بين معدلات السجن العالية تاريخيًا
and our low crime rate is pretty shaky.
ومعدل الجريمة المتدني متزعزعة إلى حد كبير.
It turns out that the crime rate goes up and down
يبدو أن معدل الجريمة يعلو وينخفض
irrespective of how many young people we send to prison.
بغض النظر عن عدد الشباب الذين نرسلهم إلى السجن.
We tend to think about justice in a pretty narrow way:
نميل إلى الاعتقاد بأن العدالة طريق ضيق جدًا:
good and bad, innocent and guilty.
جيد وسيء، بريء ومذنب.
Injustice is about being wrongfully convicted.
الظلم هو عن الإدانة بصورة غير شرعية.
So if you're convicted of something you did do,
لذا فإن تمت إدانتكم بشيء قمتم بفعله،
you should be punished for it.
يجب أن تعاقبوا لأجله.
There are innocent and guilty people,
هناك أناس بريئون ومذنبون،
there are victims and there are perpetrators.
هناك ضحايا وهناك مرتكبو جرائم.
Maybe we could think a little bit more broadly than that.
ربما يمكننا أن نفكر بصورة أشمل من تلك.
Right now, we're asking kids who live in the most disadvantaged neighborhoods,
حاليًا، نطلب من الأولاد الذين يعيشون في الأحياء الأكثر حرمانًا،
who have the least amount of family resources,
الذين يملكون الحد الأدنى من موارد الأسرة،
who are attending the country's worst schools,
الذين يلتحقون بأسوإ مدارس البلد،
who are facing the toughest time in the labor market,
الذين يواجهون أصعب الأوقات في سوق العمل،
who are living in neighborhoods where violence is an everyday problem,
الذين يعيشون في أحياء يكون العنف فيها مشكلة يومية،
we're asking these kids to walk the thinnest possible line --
نطلب من هؤلاء الأولاد أن يمشوا بأضيق خط ممكن --
to basically never do anything wrong.
ببساطة ألا يفعلوا أي شيء خاطئ.
Why are we not providing support to young kids facing these challenges?
لماذا لا نقدم الدعم للأولاد الصغار الذين يواجهون هذه التحديات؟
Why are we offering only handcuffs, jail time and this fugitive existence?
لماذا نقدم الأصفاد والسجن وهذا الهروب الوجودي فحسب؟
Can we imagine something better?
هل بإمكاننا تخيل شيء أفضل؟
Can we imagine a criminal justice system that prioritizes recovery,
هل بإمكاننا تخيل نظام عدالة جنائية يحدد الأولويات بين المعافاة
prevention, civic inclusion,
والحماية والإدماج المدني
rather than punishment?
بدلًا من العقوبة؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
A criminal justice system that acknowledges
نظام عدالة جنائية يعترف
the legacy of exclusion that poor people of color in the U.S. have faced
بإرث الحرمان الذي قد عانى منه الأشخاص الملونون الفقراء في الولايات المتحدة
and that does not promote and perpetuate those exclusions.
ولا يعزز ويخلد أنواع الحرمان هذه.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And finally, a criminal justice system that believes in black young people,
وأخيرًا، نظام عدالة جنائية يؤمن بالشباب السود،
rather than treating black young people as the enemy to be rounded up.
بدلًا من معامة الشباب السود كأعداء يجري جمعهم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
The good news is that we already are.
الأخبار الجيدة هي أننا كذلك.
A few years ago, Michelle Alexander wrote "The New Jim Crow,"
قبل سنوات قليلة، كتب ميشيل ألكساندر كتاب "ذا نيو جيم كرو"،
which got Americans to see incarceration as a civil rights issue
ما جعل الأمريكين يرون السجن على أنه قضية حقوق مدنية
of historic proportions in a way they had not seen it before.
ذات أبعاد تاريخية بطريقة لم يروها من قبل.
President Obama and Attorney General Eric Holder have come out very strongly
الرئيس أوباما والمدعي العام إريك هولدر أعلنا بكل قوة
on sentencing reform,
عن القيام بإصلاحات،
on the need to address racial disparity in incarceration.
عن الحاجة إلى معالجة الفروق العرقية في السجن.
We're seeing states throw out Stop and Frisk
نحن نرى ولاياتٍ تقوم بالإيقاف والتفتيش
as the civil rights violation that it is.
وهو انتهاك للحقوق المدنية.
We're seeing cities and states decriminalize possession of marijuana.
نرى مدنًا وولاياتٍ تشرِّع حيازة الماريجوانا.
New York, New Jersey and California
نيويورك ونيوجيرسي وكاليفورنيا
have been dropping their prison populations, closing prisons,
تخفض من عدد نزلاء سجونها وتقفل السجون،
while also seeing a big drop in crime.
بينما نرى أيضًا هبوطًا في معدل الجريمة.
Texas has gotten into the game now,
تكساس تنضم إلى ذلك الآن،
also closing prisons, investing in education.
أيضًا تقفل السجون، تستثمر في التعليم.
This curious coalition is building from the right and the left,
هذا الائتلاف الفضولي يزيد من اليمين واليسار،
made up of former prisoners and fiscal conservatives,
شكله سجناء سابقون ومحافظون أميريون،
of civil rights activists and libertarians,
نشطاء حقوق مدنية وليبراليون،
of young people taking to the streets to protest police violence
شباب يخرجون إلى الشوارع للاحتجاج على عنف الشرطة
against unarmed black teenagers,
اجاه المراهقين السود غير المسلحين،
and older, wealthier people --
وأشخاص أكبر وأكثر غنى --
some of you are here in the audience --
بعضكم هنا في الجمهور --
pumping big money into decarceration initiatives
يضخون أموالًا كثيرة في مبادرات إطلاق سراح السجناء.
In a deeply divided Congress,
في الكونغرس المنقسم بعمق،
the work of reforming our criminal justice system
العمل على إصلاح نظام العدالة الجنائية لدينا
is just about the only thing that the right and the left
هو الشيء الوحيد الذي يتفق عليه
are coming together on.
اليمين واليسار.
I did not think I would see this political moment in my lifetime.
لم أعتقد أنني سأرى هذه اللحظة السياسية في حياتي.
I think many of the people who have been working tirelessly
أعتقد أن الكثير من الناس الذين كانوا يعملون بلا كلل
to write about the causes and consequences
للكتابة عن أسباب ونتائج
of our historically high incarceration rates
معدل السجن العالي تاريخيًا عندنا
did not think we would see this moment in our lifetime.
لم يعتقدوا أننا سنرى هذه اللحظة في حياتنا.
The question for us now is, how much can we make of it?
السؤال بالنسبة لنا الآن هو، ماذا سنحقق من ذلك؟
How much can we change?
كم نستطيع أن نتغير؟
I want to end with a call to young people,
أريد أن أختم بدعوة إلى الشباب،
the young people attending college
الشباب الذين يذهبون إلى الكلية
and the young people struggling to stay out of prison
والشباب الذين يكافحون للبقاء خارج السجن
or to make it through prison and return home.
أو لاجتياز مرحلة السجن والعودة للديار.
It may seem like these paths to adulthood are worlds apart,
ربما تبدو هذه الطرق نحو البلوغ عوالم منفصلة،
but the young people participating in these two institutions
ولكن الشباب المشاركين في هاتين المؤسستين
conveying us to adulthood,
ينقلوننا نحو البلوغ،
they have one thing in common:
لديهم شيء واحد مشترك:
Both can be leaders in the work of reforming our criminal justice system.
كلاهما يستطيعان أن يكونا قادة في عمل إصلاح نظامنا للعدالة الجنائية .
Young people have always been leaders in the fight for equal rights,
كان الشباب دومًا قادة في النضال من أجل الحقوق المتساوية،
the fight for more people to be granted dignity
النضال من أجل منح الكرامة
and a fighting chance at freedom.
والفرصة في الحرية لأشخاص أكثر.
The mission for the generation of young people
إن المهمة بالنسبة لجيلنا الشاب
coming of age in this, a sea-change moment, potentially,
الذي يعيش هذا الوضع، لحظة تغيير جذري، من المحتمل،
is to end mass incarceration and build a new criminal justice system,
لإنهاء السجن الجماعي وبناء نظام عدالة جنائية جديد
emphasis on the word justice.
تأكيدًا على عدالة العالم.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)